Okay. It seems like everybody is out of the waiting room,
So we're gonna get started.
The first,
order of business, I'm gonna call to order the Monday, July 13, 2026,
Town of Andover Board of Selectmen regular meeting.
And our first item is the pledge of allegiance.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of The United States Of America
and to the republic for which it stands, one nation under God, indivisible,
with liberty and justice for all.
And we're gonna get going on public speak. We have a a large
item. We have our,
select people, so please keep your, comments
quick.
And the members that are
are going to be,
speaking regarding their letter of intent for the Board of Selectmen,
I'm not gonna call on you during public speak unless anyone has any specific reason or they wanna add.
Anybody?
No? Okay. Wally, you're up.
Nothing at this time, Jeff. Thank you. Okay.
Diane Greiner.
>> No. I'm all set also. Thank you. I see you have a very busy evening, and good luck to y'all. Alright.
Zoom user. Oh, that's wrong. Sorry. Scott Soyet.
>> Hi. I do have something quick. It's procedural,
not political.
Right now, there are three of you on this five member board,
and the charter section four zero three says the majority of the entire board is what's needed to adopt anything,
not a majority of who happens to be seated.
So that means tonight, with the three of you here, every vote you take has to be unanimous.
All three of you. One no or even an abstention and the motion fails. And if any of you asked to step out of the room, you would not have a quorum at all.
This is a real constraint on a pretty full agenda, and it lasts until those two seats are filled. So my suggestion is really simple. The item on filling the two vacancies is down at 10 d,
more than halfway through the agenda. I would ask that you just consider moving up front instead right after additions and changes.
It is properly worn, so moving it to is no problem. And the charter says that once you appoint someone, they'd be sworn in forthwith.
That is section,
four zero eight, I think. So Roberta can do that right here if she's on. I actually haven't looked.
So if you fill those seats early, get folks sworn in, you can have a functioning board for the rest of the night instead of one that needs unanimous three for every single item. That's it. Thank you.
>> Wally, I'm not sure if that's your wife,
Carol.
I have another Wally on the board.
She's here. She's got no problem at
>> K.
And Wally, you have two units set up. So if you turn one of them off,
it'll stop any feedback if you need to talk.
Tess Grouse.
All set.
Okay. Valerie Bruno.
All set. Thank you. Ben Harp.
>> Oh, I forgot that. Sorry. Nick's iPhone.
All set. Thank you.
Stephen King.
>> Real quick, I wanted to,
just on behalf of ASC, thanks for the bench that the,
town donated,
at the, two hundred and fiftieth,
anniversary
or birthday,
celebration that we had at the club.
We've got that displayed at our upper clubhouse. Appreciate that.
We raised a
number of, donations,
I think close to $900 and number of food items.
And, it was a good day overall with, some great turnout. The only criticism that I had and that I heard is we had,
no representation by our elected officials. But other than that, it was a successful day. Thanks.
Louise Goodwin.
I'm all set. Thanks. Shannon Lyle. I
>> didn't plan this, but I just wanted to echo what Scott Soyette had said, which is to strongly encourage you to move item 10 to the top of your agenda
simply to seat two other board of select members, which to me seems your top priority for tonight. Good luck. Thanks.
And thank you to Stephen King and the Sportsman's Club
for a terrific two hundred and fiftieth celebration.
Really appreciated being able to use your space.
And Anne Creme was there. Bye.
Heather Van Carra.
I'm all set. Thanks. Joanne Ebert.
>> I'm looking forward to the process,
tonight and just here to listen. Thank you. Liz Loketch.
I don't really have anything,
tonight. Just good luck.
A phone number ending in 5475?
>> Yes. This is Leanne Hutchinson. I have nothing at this time. Thanks anyway.
Jesse?
I'm good. Thank you very much.
Marcy Minor?
Okay. Caitlin McIntosh?
>> I'm all set. Just looking forward to see Matt actually get a contract because I think he can do some great things for our town. Thank you.
Leanne Hutchinson?
Yes.
Thanks anyway. I'm all set.
>> Kimberly Prasan?
All set for now. Thank you. All right. Did I miss anyone?
>> Yeah. I had a tough
time getting on. Yeah. Go ahead. Just really quick. I didn't get a chance to look at see if there's any new additions or anything, but
I just wanted to remind
you guys that
a lot of
part of the board of selectmen is hiring and firing and managing people.
And so when you look at your applicants,
hopefully you'll hire
or select someone
that
is good at that.
And
even if you only pick one, at least you have one.
So
I know it sounds like you have a lot of good applicants. So anyway,
thank you.
>> Okay. Anybody else did I miss?
Okay.
We're now gonna move on to a decision changes to the agenda.
So I would like to
we'll start with the deletion. I would like to delete item 10A,
discussion and action on the AES operating budget funding procedure.
And I would like to add an executive session
following
the interviews
and the selection
the interviews of the candidates for the Board of Selectmen.
And I would like to move item 10 a up to between item six and seven, which is after resignations and before the town administrator's
report.
Anybody have anything 10
d.
>> Moving up. 10 d. 10 d. 10 d.
Anybody else? Scott or Anne, do you have any other changes to the agenda that you'd like to make? Nope. Thank you. Okay.
So let's vote on that.
Oh, who seconded that?
I'll second it. Anne seconded it.
>> Further discussion, no? Anne, how do you vote?
Nothing.
Scott?
Three.
And Jeff McGuire, aye. So that's three nothing.
Okay.
So let's
get started. We're going to go on to item four, board and commission presentations. Matt, we don't have any?
That
is correct.
Okay. Board appointments,
we don't have any.
>> Excuse me. Do we need to say the reason for our executive session?
>> I I the reason for the executive session is to discuss the candidates for
Yes. Thank you. The board of selectmen.
We don't have, well, actually, we do have an appointment,
Matt. And I don't think, the information is in our packet, but we're we need to make everybody aware that there was an individual that was hired at the community center as the assistant. So, Matt, why don't you give us some information on her? Yes. So
>> happy to announce that we hired an assistant for
Tess at the community center and senior center.
Her name is Kate Cox. She lives just over the line in Columbia, but she has a lot of experience, brings some energy to
and I think she'll be very valuable. We've
we've put her on and
just have her introduce herself at a at a future meeting.
>> Okay.
Alright.
Item six, any resignations?
No. Just gonna we don't have any.
>> First time in a few of my few meetings. Mr. Chairman, I don't know if did we ever take up the, the actual resignations last time or did we? We did. We did. Okay. Just wanna make sure.
>> Do we have any more is my question. Mhmm. Okay. That's a great meeting. That's a good start.
Let's move on. So now we're gonna move on to 10 d, which is the discussion and action on new board of selectmen members. We had, six,
residents put in letters of intent.
We have one of the applicants, Ryan Fitch. He has,
withdrawn,
his name from consideration, so we now have five members.
What we're going to attempt to do is
we're going to give each one of the candidates
some time in public to express themselves as to why they're looking to join the board and
what skills they might bring to the board and and how we can all move forward. So
the process for this will be you'll have three to five minutes to discuss
what you want to and then Anne and Scott and myself will have an opportunity to ask you a couple of questions.
We're gonna try to make this as painless as possible, and and it's more about you guys expressing your desire to join the board. So I'm gonna go in the order as to their listed on the agenda. So we're gonna start with Ron Alengli.
And please tell me how I pronounce that Ron.
And I hope you're not having problems with there you go. There you go. I got it now. Yeah.
>> Langlois.
Just like Yeah. You
Okay. So I submitted my letter in just to I would like to join the board and
bring some of my knowledge that I've had over thirty six years of working in a big company, Connecticut Natural Gas,
where I started in the field and I actually worked my way up to management where I was managing
customer service, 75 people, dealing with union and non union issues.
Being in the town for fifteen years, my wife and myself,
we've grown to like the town a lot, met a few people,
got a lot more to meet.
Now that I retired, I retired in 2025
in the beginning of the year.
Just listening more now to
board finance meetings, board steward meetings,
paying a little more attention to what's going on, that I have a little more time to do that.
Feeling that the knowledge that I had learned
over my years experience dealing with all kinds of issues,
I'd like to bring that to the board,
feeling that we could try to get everything to work together
so that,
you know it sometimes seems like we've got issues where it's the school against the town and all that.
And I'd like to try and just make it one
so that when we do go for a vote we're not voting two and three times spending
town money to do that because it costs us money every time we have to vote.
And I feel that we can. I feel that we can come to that conclusion.
Also there you know it's a beautiful town. I want to keep it the way the rustic
ness that it is. I think that attracts a lot of people but we also need to be able to all be able to live here and financially look forward to it here too.
So, I'm feeling that a lot of the stuff that I've learned by managing budgets over the years and by dealing with union and non union issues and we were able to come to decisions and dealing with towns all over the place and cities,
working with all kinds of people.
We've always were able to come to a decision together.
Yelling and screaming never saw that is how I felt. So those are my skills that I've learned over the years and I would like to bring them to the town
to see if we can all work together and work and get things to to be one.
I I've done a lot of what you were saying like Marcy was saying. We've we've had the fire. We've had to hire. We've had people sometimes that we hired. We weren't happy with afterwards.
I've done a lot of that.
It's
just bringing, like I said, I like to just put my input into the town and
make improvements in the town, but still keeping it a rural town, but being able to have the elderly live here,
people that want to come in with kids and have them attend our schools, the whole nine yards.
That's what I have.
>> Okay,
well thank you very much.
Anne and Scott,
do you guys have any questions for Ron?
>> What qualifications
do you have to you
know what? The Board of Selectmen
here, we do a lot of stuff other than come to a meeting once a month. We always have projects.
Anne has projects. Jeff has plenty of projects. So what skills do you have to help us with different projects that could come along?
>> Skills with I've I've done everything in the field from,
you know, looking I've I've got
electrical background. I've got gas background. I have construction, a little bit of construction background,
drainage background,
all kinds of stuff that I've dealt with over the years with that.
I hopefully that feels that I could I could help with what's going on and work on some of these projects.
Do you does the board actually do the projects themselves? Or they just get a team together and make stuff work?
>> No, we get a team. Scott
is probably the one that's most hands on on
the execution of given projects.
You know, we all have our strengths in different areas. So,
but as
we continue to work, you know, there's some projects that we're much more involved in.
And there are some projects that what we'll do is we'll just manage the contractor. So like, let's say the bridge round, we're not doing the project, we're managing,
we're working with the town administrator to manage the project. Scott will be down there every day watching what they're doing. So
my
question is, and it'll be pretty much the same to everybody, you know, where do you see our town going? What's your vision for what you want our town to be?
What direction are you trying, would you want to take it in as a Board of Selectment Member?
>> I would like to see our town
have a little bit more in a business area but not like a big store to help with taxes in town. I would like to see like, you know, a little more moms and pops stores come in and and do stuff on like where we have the strips on Route 6 over there. I know we have a project coming in for apartments that
I think that would help too if that goes forward and ends up going through.
But I feel that I don't want to make it like I grew up in the city and I don't want to make it become a city. I don't want to see that. I would like to see it remain at like quiet town.
But be able to financially support stuff.
Going in a direction that we're going in, I don't think financially a lot of elderly people who have been here all their lives can be able to stay and afford it here and I would like to see that continue
so that they can stay in their houses as long as they can and be able to stay here not have to worry about affordability.
And but I want to keep it a a rural town, but I think we need a couple of small businesses and I think that would help improve things along the way a little bit.
Okay.
Anybody else have anything for Ron?
Ron,
>> thank you very much. I appreciate it. Thank you all for giving me the time. I appreciate that.
One
second.
There we go. Jacqueline
Langlen.
>> Hi. How are you? Good. How are you? Good.
Good.
It's Lanigan. Lanigan is Lanigan. There you are. Lanigan.
So
first, I'm gonna start with why am I here? I'm here because I love Andover,
And I'm gonna start by reading some of what I sent in so I feel like that gives a fair idea of who I am.
I moved to Andover when I was 10 years old.
I'm 55 right now.
I attended Andover Elementary School, Ray of Middle School, and high school. I graduated in 1989.
I worked at a few of the local businesses growing up, Andover Pizza,
what is
the gas station at the end of 03/16 used to be Jasper's.
So I had a clear idea of most of the town original town people back then.
The town the town guys,
just
the general Andover people.
Later,
not more recently, in 2019,
I worked for Du Bois Automotive.
So some people on here might recognize me from there. I ran into several people from town.
So
I feel like I've met quite a few people or know quite a few people or dynamics in Andover,
clear idea of the town.
My parents live in town on Basola Road.
I am currently living on Route 6,
with my boyfriend who his family grew up in town. I also have an apartment on Center Street.
Like I said, I have a lot going on in this town.
I have two adult children,
30 and 26.
I have three grandchildren, a five year old, a three year old, and a one year old. So I feel like I have a good idea of just the general
needs
of different
types of people in town,
and I think that's a strength for me.
Me personally,
as a person, I'm a listener.
I listen to what everybody has to say.
I want to hear everyone's opinion
before I form an
idea of what direction I'm gonna I'm gonna listen to everyone's opinion
calmly and with common sense.
I graduated from Manchester Community College with a paralegal degree, so I have I'm familiar with a lot of law.
That's a strength for me. That would be a strength in the town for me. I have no problem working with people or trying to understand
a lot.
Currently,
I work for a beer distributor.
I am a sales manager.
I cover three counties, Hartford, Wyndham, and Tolland County. I work with all types of people all day long, whether they're in a good mood, a bad mood, or an even mood.
So
I also recently completed sixty hours of a real estate agent class.
So I have a clear understanding
of real estate
and what's
going on currently
and the laws that go with it. That was all part of the class and part of the course and the exams.
Right now, I am a member of the RTC.
I am their treasurer.
I love it. I love being the treasurer. I actually went in and have just
kinda
taken off from there going into
all of these different Andover elements.
So that's that's kinda it. That's the gist of me and who I am. I think I'm a good fit with you guys. I really do.
I think I can calmly listen
and make common sense decisions.
And I'm helpful, and I'm also a quick learner of everything.
That's it.
>> Alright. Thank you very much. You're welcome. Anne Anne and Scott?
>> Oh, Jackie, where why do you wanna be a selectman in the town of Andover?
>> Because I think I'll make a great selectman in the town of Andover.
I wanna be a selectman because I wanna have a voice in town. I wanna make sure that the town
I wanna be that that's I wanna be a leader in the town. I wanna represent,
Andover residents.
I do. I think I will do a good job of doing that. I really do. I'm a listener.
I don't
that's that's the basic for me. I mean, is there a further question than that?
>> Well, I'll ask. And
yeah.
Jackie, I'd just ask you, you know, the same question. Where
Where do you see Andover going? What do you think you
where would you as a select person like to take the town?
>> Andover,
I love the town that it is,
but I also know that it needs growth.
There's different areas of town.
I I see needs.
I definitely see
some needs for some housing
more specifically
towards our elderly.
I don't I I talk to enough to know that we don't really have too much here as far as housing.
You know? If you can't stay in your house, okay.
They're having to move out of Andover, and that's I don't know that I like that. You stay in town.
I think that there should be some type of Andover Plaza is not what it used to be at all. There was a market in town somewhere where people could go and get groceries.
We don't have that.
We we should have that. That's a major loss here,
I think.
People are going out of town to go to the store. Dollar General,
you know, I go to
Manchester, Polchester, Williman, to the big grocery stores or even Ted's in Hebron. We don't have that.
There's definitely a lot to look at of what the actual needs are. We need a tax base.
You know?
Just has to be smart and it has to be in the right places.
It can't just be
haywire,
I guess is the right way of wording it.
>> Okay.
Scott or Anne, do have anything else that you'd like to ask Jackie?
I think she's covered a lot.
Okay.
>> Jackie, thank you very much. Appreciate it. Thank you, Jeff.
Dave Gustanian.
>> Good evening.
I've lived in Andover for about thirty two years.
I raised my family here.
I have, two adult daughters
who've done, gone through the school system and have done very well in Andover.
I love the community.
I got, involved
with the community starting in the fire department,
thirty one years ago.
I've moved up to where I'm a captain
EMT firefighter,
president of the association.
I was involved in many committees within,
Andover,
started out with the zoning board of appeals.
I was a member of the Board of Finance for many years.
I believe I was the treasurer at one time.
That was very, rewarding and a lot of work.
From there, I was on the
RAM Board of Ed,
which was a
challenge,
but it was very rewarding. We hired a superintendent,
principal,
did a lot of negotiations
with them.
So I've I've done a lot, I believe, within within
the community.
For my
work side,
I've been
an IT computer person for forty five years,
worked with large firms like Deloitte,
Aetna, some of the other companies. I was a director at one time with a small software development firm
The last, since 2000 and
or 1995,
I've been with the Hartford
and IBM
back
still working at the Hartford, but back as an employee with IBM.
I'll be retiring
in August,
so I'll have a lot more time to devote to this.
I do believe my family has been extended
family and my
local family have always believed in
bringing back to the community and adding to the community and volunteering is very important.
So I think I think some of the skills that I have would
be a good fit
within the board of selectmen.
>> Okay. Alright. Thank you very much.
And Scott?
Well, I'll go then. For real.
Dave, you can, you can hold on. Dave, you
know, the same question that I really asked the other members that have gone before you is like, where do you see the town going? What, what, what do you think from
your position if we pointed you to the board of selectmen? Where would you want the town to go and what would you like to see happen?
>> Well,
I would definitely work with the other board members of the board to see what their thoughts are. I think a responsible growth, a way to
grow the tax base and not lose the character of Andover.
You know, I I think, some
businesses that would add to the town,
and
I could see
that
the senior housing is definitely a challenge.
I think there's
the Hop River Homes is a is an excellent place, but I think there's a long waiting list. And,
there's a lot of different things that could be done, but I would work with the community and the board of selectmen to,
to help with that.
Okay.
Thank you. Scott?
>> Dave, you're being on the fire department for a long time. You'll have plenty of time for the board of selectmen also?
>> I I believe so. You know, now that I'll I'll be retiring in August, I think, I'll definitely have more time.
You know, the fire department is, is an important,
thing for me, but I definitely will have,
more time for that,
for the Selectmen. Absolutely.
>> Been doing a lot of things in the town over the years. And what do you think is the most important thing you've done?
>> I think being a member of the fire department has been very rewarding and important.
I've met a lot of people in town in a lot of
difficult
times,
and I think I've made a difference there, and I I I hope I have.
I I really enjoy meeting a lot of people and helping.
You know, getting up at two in the morning when somebody needs help is is is a challenge. And there's not a lot of there's a few of us that are left that have been there that long. There's even been some people who've been there longer, but, I I find that the most rewarding.
I did really enjoy,
being on the, the board of ed, the RAM board of ed, and that was one of the things that
I always tried working with the three towns.
I always try to impress on people is that,
you
know, we need an import a a good school, but we also have to remember that the whole community needs to be able to afford
to pay these pay this bill. And
I it
was a lot of seniors had talked to me and and said that they were, struggling
with taxes.
But I think probably the fire department
has been
my biggest rewarding experience.
>> K.
Anybody else?
Dave, thank you very much. Appreciate it. Dave.
Ben Harp,
are you on?
You are there. Can you hear me?
I can. Do you have a camera?
Can you see me now?
>> No.
Okay.
If that's the best we're gonna get, let's go.
>> Okay.
I've lived in town eight years,
married, have one kid that's currently at AES.
I'm a combat veteran.
I managed
as a senior NCO anywhere from 30 to a 147
service members.
I'm currently semi retired.
I own multiple businesses.
One of the biggest reasons why I wanna be a board of selectmen is I listen to
the budget process,
and I took to note when you said that the
current financial system of the town is unsustainable.
So I started looking at the numbers.
Since 2016,
this town has lost 60% of its businesses.
Currently, right now, we have 11 prop residential properties for sale on the market. The average is ninety days before it's sold.
The town needs businesses to help pay the tax revenue.
The town is only getting older.
55%
of the town is 52 years or older.
As for other experiences,
being a business owner, I have been part of the grant process, grant writing,
going after grants,
stuff like that. I have a construction background as well, so I can read blueprints,
do the permit process, manage build sites, and stuff like that.
If anybody has any questions, you can fire away.
>> And it's Scott.
Alright. Then I'll go with my first my question.
Anne, go ahead.
>> Was just thinking about how you've asked the other people about why they wanna be on the board of selectmen. So I guess you sort of answered it, but if you have anything else to add.
>> For me, it's stability of the town. As you guys in the very beginning of the meeting, you've had a lot of turnover in the town, whether it's regular,
maintenance positions,
board of selectmen
resigning,
etcetera, etcetera.
And being a younger person in the town,
I would like to be like everybody in this room and live in the town thirty, forty, fifty years.
And
the best way I see to do that is to get into a leadership position and
help keep the town going north.
>> Okay. So, Ben, I'll I'll ask you my question, which is,
if we appointed you to this position, where would you like to sit there and see what would you and your attributes, where would you take the town
working with the rest of the board?
>> My expertise is more on the business side of things, so I would like to get us back to that 2016
time period when the town had 200 plus businesses in the town.
I would do
one of my biggest priorities would be getting utilities ran on Route 6 so that we could monetize
the areas on Route 6 because, like, the housing development that wants to go in,
one of their biggest holdups is the septic and utilities.
And in the future, that's gonna prevent us from getting
any kind of business
into Route 6. So, like, right now, Scotts Electric is on the fence about staying or leaving
because they wanna expand their business,
but
they don't know if they can because the building is 50 years old.
And with the utility situation,
they wanna add a 100 to a 150 employees. But with, you know, with running on septic tanks, it's gonna be a problem. So
K.
Scott, do you have anything?
Good.
>> K.
And anything else?
Alright, Ben. Thank you very much. Appreciate it. You're welcome. Alright.
Ryan has withdrawn,
so we're on to,
Christine Randazzo.
Hi, everybody.
Can you hear me okay?
Yes. We can. Okay. Thank you. My
>> name is Christine Randazzo.
I have been a resident in Andover for twenty eight years.
I have two boys.
My husband and I have two boys that we've raised in town. They've gone through the school's educational system
as well as ran middle school and high school, and they had fantastic education background. We're really, really thrilled that they were able to have that.
I am a local business owner in town. I own Randazzo Design and Associates.
We are a women owned and operated
landscape design and lawn fertilization
company. We've been in business for twenty three years.
I am a category 3A pesticide supervisory
operator
that allows me to provide those types of lawn care
services and pest control services
for golf courses,
commercial, residential,
and municipalities.
I am also a civil engineer.
I have worked for the state of Connecticut, Bureau of Engineering Highway Operations.
I was an engineer for the town of Manchester
and also worked for
a consulting. So I've seen all all aspects
of the design, build, planning, zoning, permitting processes
from a state perspective,
a municipality,
and from a consulting perspective.
I do think I have a lot to offer this town. I I do understand how towns are run as well as state
you know, from the background that I have.
And
I think I could
provide a lot of support and guidance
to
all aspects of the town from public works
budgeting.
I would be thrilled to serve on the Board of Selectmen.
I want to positively shape our community's future.
I really want to ensure
that our resources align with the residents'
needs,
and I also want to foster a more connected and thriving town. I I think that the world is so divided today, and everybody's always choosing a side. And I think we're stronger in numbers, and if we come together
and unite, we can do a lot much we can do so much more and move further than we have in the past,
and I really wanna facilitate that move.
I've also done just some volunteer work in the town recently.
We just finished the project
at Long Hill, the field improvements, where we just finished installing
the playgrounds, the four pickleball courts, and the pavilions.
That
was a two and a half year project,
and we had a great committee
that worked together tirelessly to get that done, and I think it's a great asset for the town. We need things like that
to support our town, to keep people here, to to attract people that want to come here.
I I don't think it's
you should have to leave town for every single service that you need in town. So it's nice that we have something in our back in our backyard.
I also have just done some support work. I worked with Kathy Derozier in selecting
the plants for the community center.
From a non volunteer aspect,
I do provide fertilization
services for the
memorial field and the community center.
I also have
provided,
I did eradicate
some large stands of
Japanese knotweed, which is the number two invasive species in the state of Connecticut,
right in the area on Office Center Street, where the parking area is to the bike path.
There were some targeted areas that were just really running amok, and it's one of the most difficult weeds to reel in.
And we were able to successfully do that actually in a year's time, which is great because that is a stinker.
Yeah, I think that's all I have. If you have any questions, I'm happy to answer.
And Scott?
Everything I was gonna ask her, she already answered.
>> K.
Christine, I'll ask you the same question I've asked everybody else.
If
we point you to the Board of Selectmen, what's the direction that you are looking to work with us and where would you like to see the time go?
>> I would like to work with you folks just to, so we can collaboratively put together our heads and
steer the town in a way that benefits
all ages, young and old.
I would like to attract businesses
that can help the tax base in the town while maintaining its rural charm.
And I think I could work with the departments in town just to
spearhead
initiatives
of
tasks that need to be done to try to figure out
how we can do them more efficiently
and productively.
Anne, do you have anything?
Additional.
No.
>> Okay.
I do have to go back through everyone for just one quick thing.
We cannot appoint a Democrat to this committee. We can appoint any other political affiliation. So I just want to make sure that I'm not, we're not doing something that we shouldn't be doing. So, Dave, I'm going to start with you. You are registered.
>> I am registered Republican.
Jacqueline, registered Republican because you're on the committee? Yes, I am. Okay.
>> And Ron, registered Republican because you are on the committee? Correct. Or are you, you know, you are Yes. Registered Republican.
Okay.
Ben Harp?
Yes. Registered Republican.
Alright. And Christine Randazzo?
Same. Registered Republican.
>> Okay.
So we're not gonna run afoul of any issues
appointing any one of you. Okay. So that's good.
Anybody else? Anne or Scott, you got anything else you want to ask anybody else before we go to Executive Session?
Okay.
All right. I'm going to make a motion that we go to executive session. I'm going to put, before we do this, I'm going to put everybody in, I'm going to stop the recording. After we vote, I'm going to put everybody into the waiting room. And as soon as Anne and Scott and myself are done deliberating,
we'll come back out and we'll go back into the regular meeting. Okay?
Someone want to second the motion to go to executive session?
Second.
>> We'll give it to Anne. Anne seconded. So
all those in favor?
Aye. Okay.
>> One second.
Okay. So I'm going to resume the recording and I'm going to call the meeting back to order
after
ending the executive session. So
first of all, really do want to thank all of the individuals who
put themselves out there for
this position.
Know, it was a very difficult decision.
And what
I want to stress to everybody is that we need everyone to be engaged in town and to,
the more people that we have that are interested in
serving the town in any position, whether it's on any board, whether it's the Board of Selectmen or it's, you know, the Rec Commission. It does help the town and it allows
us to continue to have
a
group of people that will continue to move the town forward as we move from election to election. So first of all, thank you very much for participating
and we
will,
we appreciate you guys putting yourselves out there. So thank you.
So
I'm gonna sit there and I'll make the motion because we
were in agreement in
exec succession. So I'm gonna make a motion that we appoint to the board of selectmen,
Dave Gestanian and Christine Randazzo
as I second that, members of the Board of Selectmen.
Scott voted.
Scott seconded.
Okay.
Anne, how do you vote?
Scott,
how do you vote?
Alright. Jeff Maguire, aye.
Thank you very much, everyone. We greatly appreciated
that.
Dave and Christine,
we're not going to swear you in tonight. What I would ask you to do is to go to the town clerk's office tomorrow
and to sit there and
Roberta will swear you in and
you can go in and meet Matt and you can sit there and meet the rest of the crew at the town offices. And then we'll have you,
we'll get with you before our meet next meeting and we'll sit there and get you all the information we can to get you up to speed with the things that are going on. All right.
All right. Thank you.
One second.
>> Okay. I do have the recording going. Correct? Okay.
We are now moving on to item seven, the town administrator's
report. So Matt, you're up.
>> All right. Good evening, everyone. Can you hear me?
We can. Okay, great. So
as I mentioned earlier that we did have the
new staff at the community center.
Going into the
when we did the packet, we only had
we had one person who was interested in the transfer station attendant.
From what I understand from Kate, that we did have somebody express interest today that they
gonna they took an application. They're gonna fill it out.
So we'll see how that moves. On the on the public buildings custodial
custodian,
we had
no increase but also today, somebody come and asked for information
about that and also took an application.
Going into
the weekend,
my suggestion was that a lot of the
it was more of a we're talking about possibly reposting
it as more of a just a custodian
as opposed to some minor
repairs to get done. Some of the things that were in the the job description included
cleaning the gutters and those type of things,
minor repairs.
>> And that But why don't why don't we, Matt, just make sure that we split those two jobs? We we try to find a handyman,
and we have someone for cleaning services.
Okay. Right. And then I would sit there and recommend that, you know, even in the interim, we find someone to come in and do an initial cleaning of the town hall because we were spoiled.
And we wanna make sure that, you know, we keep the town hall looking as best we can.
>> Okay.
Yes.
Had a meeting last week about the Long Hill Bridge, replacing coordination,
moving forward.
We're on schedule.
We're still trying to get Frontier to move some of their their lines that we're hoping to have that done. But, the big news is that project is on schedule.
I know that we've heard earlier that the Veterans Field project had its grand opening.
There's a couple of final items that we've done including the parking lots and handicap spaces, but those will be taken care of in the short term.
This morning I met with the engineer
that's helping with the Lake Road, Basola Road culvert projects and
talked about the next step, which is the town getting easements. We got a letter of work with
Dennis O'Brien formulate
the
letters that we're going go out. We're probably going to meet individually with
the different property come
to some sort of agreement so that we can get the easements taken care of that we can go get
this out to bid the fall.
As mentioned, the diesel fuel system at the public works, ordered the GIR
is in, but they're still waiting on the pump and installation, but we anticipate
that within the next four to five weeks.
Just continuing to move on about the accounts and procurement,
processing invoices,
I've become a signatory on several of the accounts. We do have the audit coming up. The auditor will be coming to the finance committee meeting on July 22,
And
we are I even just talked today with the first elect on the we're moving forward as far as the collecting bargain bargaining on the expiring contract
that we have with AFSCME.
So playing some pre negotiation
strategy with the select and the board of finance member
and perhaps the DPW
superintendent.
Then at some point, we'll get together with the union and move forward to see what
both sides want moving forward.
Other than that, I'm here to answer any questions. That's most of the report. I know it's a little
bit into the meeting, but happy to hear any have any questions.
On the diesel fuel,
the GIR is the software?
That's correct. It's the, the software for that.
>> Okay.
And then,
item seven, the town audit,
that is an audit presentation
for the prior audit?
That would be for the, the year ending,
06/30/2025.
>> Okay.
Alright. So that is the auditor reviewing
those statements with the various boards to get an understanding of how that information
all flows together. And
>> I believe that Lisa has set up a date when the auditor is gonna come in to start the the current fiscal year, well, the one that just ended, the f y '26
that closed on June 30. So that'll be coming up.
I know I have a date somewhere. May have been the first week of August.
But, yeah, we'll be starting on that while it's still fresh in everybody's mind.
>> Okay.
Ian or Scott, you have any questions for Matt?
Okay. Alright. Thank you.
>> Well,
actually, before we get away from Matt's
section, I
need to make a motion just because we need to make this official. So I'm gonna make a motion to
approve the hiring of Kate McCarthy Cox as the assistant,
director of the
well, Tess, please tell me your title or Matt, what's her official title?
She's the, assistant community
center,
director.
>> Okay. So I'll make a motion to appoint
Kate McCarthy Cox as the assistant
community center director.
That's it.
I'll second that.
>> We're
going to give that one to Scott and he went- he got his voice out first. All right. So Scott
seconded it.
Any further discussion? We'll vote on that. Anne, how do you vote?
Okay.
Scott, how do you vote? Aye.
>> I vote yes. So three nothing.
Okay.
We're gonna move on to item eight, the treasurer's report starting in page nine.
There is the,
budget to actual report
for,
the period July through June.
So if you guys have any questions,
the treasurer is actually on vacation. She is,
picking blueberries at her family farm,
so she will not be attending tonight.
>> Is that up to date? It's actual?
You think that everything is accurate there, Jeff?
>> I it is. It is up to date as far as the reconciliations. Reconciliations,
I know Matt signed off on those, but are are I believe that
all of the reconciliations have been prepared for,
through
June 30.
So
the
issues that are going to have to be addressed related to this or any of the over budgeted items, Scott, there are a couple lines that are over budget.
We're definitely going to come in under budget. It would be my mind. I don't know if all of
the year end transactions,
there's some accruals for payroll that need to sit there being processed,
but I don't sit there and see them putting us in a,
in any kind of negative position. So,
we just need to sit there and make the transfers. And hopefully by
the time that the treasurer gets back, we can sit there and get that accomplished and get this done. But all of the bank accounts are reconciled.
As a secondary note, the,
you know, we talked a little bit last meeting that
we had a total of 25 or 26 bank accounts.
24 of those accounts have been, 21 of those accounts have been closed
and the money moved into the interest bearing account for the town.
So,
you know,
we're a fund balance accounting for the town, so the funds are still there, but the money is now earning interest.
So,
those those dollars were transferred in July 1,
and we will sit there and be closing all those accounts. We're consolidating down to a total of four bank accounts.
And just so everybody understands them when you get to sit there and see the balance
sheet that the treasurer should be able to sit there and get to you by our next meeting,
You have
you have an investment account that all of the
money from the tax collector goes into. That earns interest at about two and a half percent.
You have an operating account, which is sweep account. It, it, the bank requires us to keep a $600,000
balance in that account to avoid any bank fees.
That account is where all of the checks come out of. And what happens is it's a sweep account.
So
as checks are drawn down on that account, the money from the bank transfers money from the investment account in to cover and get back to the $600,000
balance. So we have that one. And then we have another account that is
a depository
account for the tax collector for all of the credit card transactions.
And,
we have a STIF account, and that STIF account earns interest, you know, it's, it's about three and a 3.25
to 3.5%
right now it changes, but that's the STIF account. So we're down to those accounts
and,
it's gonna make the treasurer's life,
slightly easier.
And we're
gonna make and maximize as much earning potential as we can for the funds the town has.
>> Honestly, I think it's gonna be a little bit more than slightly easier.
>> Well, we had 21 accounts, Scott, and the accounts had
no functional
activity.
So
it's, it's a, it will definitely be easier. It won't be that much easier, but it will be easier. And what it'll do is it'll allow us to consolidate our information. So we will know what we have in total cash. We will know what interest
rate it's earning at, and we won't have anything sitting there
not earning interest,
which is the goal.
But there are some accounts here that I was reviewing that we need to sit there and make some budget transfers.
And we need to sit there and see,
we need to get those to the Board of Finance for their next meeting.
And,
hopefully
we can get that done so Matt can look at it and Lisa can look at it and we can sit there and make the adjustments we need to.
So go ahead, Matt.
>> So I I just wanted to mention that, yeah. Know you keep you mentioned the stiff accounts. So so people understand that the, Connecticut State Treasurer is called the short short term investment fund, and it's just called colloquially stiff for short, but it's where the state has this program where the municipalities can invest in the short term. As the first electorate said, depending the rates will move up and down, but generally they're much more
beneficial to the municipality than just sitting in a regular savings or checking account.
>> Okay.
You guys have any questions or anything that you want to address on the budget to actual?
>> I don't like the question. Maybe it's
something I don't know about. In the town garage, the fuel oil,
they spent a whole lot more than what was budgeted. It says 290%.
>> They had some issues, Ann, related to plowing and also related to when the contract expired and they ran over their total gallons,
the price was through the roof.
Yes, Yeah, know the price had gone up. You know? Okay. And it and it's and it's like that, like, where you look at where we had employee issues.
You know? And when I say employee issues, you know, we had lost our town administrator, so we had some under budget functions there. We had some over budgets in the town in the community center side. So,
you know, there's a give and take with that, but that's actually something that we'll have,
you know, Matt, if you can get us a better answer than I just provided at our next meeting, that would be appreciated on the gas. So if you can sit there and and get with Eric and with Lisa
>> and provide us a little bit more information on that, it would be helpful. Yeah. Because generally, we estimate how many you know, how much fuel we're gonna purchase when we do these when we do these
bids with other municipalities or whether it be And
once we've gone over that, then we're sort of on the spot markets. We're basically paying whatever
the current rate is plus a
few cents.
So yeah. Because this happened before I got there, let I'll look into and see what what transpired and get a report back to you. Alright? And and and also one other thing, Anne,
>> there's also budget line items for that at the school and at RAM. So we need to be billing the gallons used.
And I am not sure that the finance department has done that yet. So that could also because of that equipment
>> difficulties,
it's been hard to get that done quickly. Yeah. And and we'll sit there that.
>> We'll sit there and and get some of that stuff done. But, yes, that is also one of the reasons why the town
and what we're looking at is so far over budget.
Because I'm not positive when the last bill billing has gone out to the other entities,
you know, including the fire department. So there's three entities that have some small amount of fuel usage from there. So there's the school,
the RAM,
and that fire department all all use some level of fuel there, and those those billings need to go up.
When does our diesel contract run out?
>> I don't know that. I believe they're fit they're on the fiscal year, but I'll double check that for next month too.
>> Okay.
Alright. Alright.
If we're anybody else have any other questions or anything else they want to address?
Okay.
We'll move on to
item
nine,
it's old business and discuss and act upon.
9A, review the status of the veteran field improvement.
Hopefully everybody, I know the three of us have had an opportunity to go down there. I know,
that, well, actually all five members of the board of selectmen have been down there and have done a lot. I know that Dave and his wife are down there playing pickleball the night of
the
grand opening. And I know Anne and Scott were there for the ribbon cutting.
And Christine did a lot of work to sit there and make sure that that project went off without a hitch. So,
I think it's it's great. I think it's
the improvement that that field needed,
which was a playground so that
the young parents can sit there and during the day, get down there and use a playground,
you know, during the school year. So I think it's great. It's great. And Christine, you did a great job on that. So thank you.
So
all right. Nine b, review the unless anybody else anybody else wanna say anything about the
veterans field improvement?
No? Down there playing now.
>> Yeah.
Dennis, are you holding something up that I'm supposed to ask you about? Or
no. You're on mute, Dennis.
Mute, Dennis. Yeah.
>> Ask to unmute. I can't unmute you, my friend. So, anyway, you weren't holding up anything. Good. Nothing. You're just waving a piece of paper in front of the camera, so I was confused.
Okay. I agree. 9B,
review the senior center, senior transportation garage status.
I
believe that, Scott is working to establish a meeting with
the con that contractor with Matt and myself to sit there and,
do that
possibly next week. Is that accurate, Scott? Tuesday.
Tuesday. Probably at 10:00.
>> Okay. Alright. As soon as you guys get a confirmed
appointment with the the potential contractor, let's get it done. So let's move that forward and
get that project completed as soon as we possibly can.
Right?
Nine c, the status of the Long Hill Bridge project.
>> Matt? We think that they finally, have broken out the last of the
abutment on the
west side of the bridge. That's the church side of the bridge. The old abutment was very firmly
entrenched, and it took a long time to get it out of there. But they finally got it out, they put the tow boulders in
in the back of it. The tow boulders are supposed to stop the current when up when they put the new abutment in.
So then they're gonna move the
steel
and
start
digging it out for the new abutment on the West Side.
That's where they are now.
Okay.
Do they see any problems
>> meeting their timeline of getting it completed by fall? No. No. They're on they're on target just like Matt says.
>> Okay. Excellent.
And you got anything you wanna address related to that? No?
Okay. We'll move on. Nine d, the status of the Percy Crook Trail preliminary plan.
Matt, have we sat there and had discussions?
Is another one that we have to sit there and schedule on a meeting. And hopefully it's something that Christine can get engaged with us on that to sit there and move that forward.
>> Yeah, that was like
third or fourth on the list of things. So I think that we were trying to, once we got some more members here that we were going to tackle that.
Obviously, the July's half over, but this summer we want to start moving forward on that,
getting information on that and trying to proceed.
>> Okay. I think the build start on that, Jeff, is that is 2028,
but the Basola
Bridge is Basola Road Bridge is 27.
>> That's what's higher. It definitely is higher. And it's just
as as we all talk and we all communicate, we just got to keep we got to move these projects along slightly faster,
pick the ones that are most important. So at our next meeting, we should really lay out maybe an agenda as to which ones we sit there and see. So we make sure that Matt is focused on the given projects that we think are the most important, the ones that needs to get done
sooner than later.
So, I mean, and I, and I do know Scott, it's not on here, but the, the generator
needs to get done. So if
there were two, the most, the two most important projects and the two that need to get accomplished,
you know, let's say this fiscal year now, because we're in a new fiscal year,
is the generator and the
building at the old firehouse
needs to get dealt with. So then we can move on to the persecuted trail, and then we can move on to potentially the connectivity
aspect of the three sixteen
walkway, which is something that we have to discuss in more in detail with the entire board.
Alright.
Anything else on 9D?
No? Okay. We'll move on to 9E and update on the AES bathroom renovation.
>> So this is Matt. I participated in the
Wednesday morning meeting and I did take a tour of the bathrooms with
the superintendent and
the project's moving along.
Start to see
actual pipes and things that are coming in there that are more modern than what was there before. But I think that it's definitely on schedule and
it's proceeding.
So, I'll give you an update next month. Hopefully, it'll be, maybe
some pictures.
>> Okay.
I attended the,
Board of Education meeting
last Wednesday.
And,
just to let everybody know there's a,
going to be, an increase to the original contract that was signed.
There was some asbestos found,
in, on the pipes and an additional 30 to $35,000
will be necessary to sit there and complete the project.
Unforeseen,
but
let everybody know that that's coming.
Alright.
Anybody else have anything related to the nine e?
Okay. We'll go to nine f. Discussion and possible action on the Hop River Home contract.
I know we've had discussions
with,
Hop River Home.
That contract is not in our packet, so I don't see us voting on that tonight.
We'll push it off
>> to We've been over this
at length, haven't we, Jeff?
>> Well, we have, but I haven't sit there and seen a final contract. Have you?
>> It's the same contract as as we've had the last two times.
>> I mean, I I don't have it, Scott. So if I don't have it in the packet, I don't wanna vote on it.
I mean, it's not like it's gonna do anything to the Hop River Homes.
I mean, they're just gonna get rebated the money.
>> So does anyone have a problem if we push it off to our next meeting? Yeah. Just make sure it's in the packet for next time so we we can put this to bed.
>> K.
Alright.
Nine g,
a website update discussion and possible action on new website committee.
I know we've discussed that. I know we've had some people that actually put names up.
Mhmm.
Important we get going on that one.
>> Yeah. That's
that's another one that we do need to go. Maybe what we do is we we get with Dave and make Dave be our point person on this one.
And he can sit there and and navigate the group. And and what I would ask in the next meeting, Matt, is that we have the names of all the people that would like to participate in that so that we can sit there and get them appointed to the committee. Okay. Right.
Nine H,
janitorial discussions.
You know, we had a little bit of this during Matt's, Matt's
administrative
report,
you know, our previous
people were great. So we're gonna have to split these jobs. There's gonna have to be a cleaning function and then repair and maintenance function,
and more of a handyman function. So,
the most important thing to do is get the cleaning
function lined up so that we can keep the town hall clean.
So we need to sit there and get that done. And so hopefully, Matt, you can sit there. We can make some adjustments to
the job description and get that posted and get someone in there as soon as possible. And we do need to probably find someone
that will
sit there and do an initial cleaning before someone is appointed because I don't wanna sit there and see the town hall get too far out of
cleanliness.
Alright?
Matt, did Susan and Willie
>> did Susan and Willie give you a list of the things that they did before they left? Yes. They did. They have a book with that information. And and just so that, you know, I've been taking care of the town hall as far as that emptying the trash and sweeping it back and taking
care of the bathroom. So it's not it's not in horrible shape, but it should not be something that the town administrator
does on a regular basis. But just for the for the time being, just to get it
for the people that especially for the people that work here to make sure that it's it's cleanly, I took care of the park blew the parking lot this this weekend. So
I think the outside is looking good too. Just but like like the first segment said, we probably need someone to come in here and do a full thorough cleaning, right, you know, just check the windows, make sure they're washed and those type of things. So it's a there's a baseline that's a clean building that they're starting with.
>> Can you just repeat one thing? What did what did you do in the driveway, the parking lot?
>> I
I basically, like, blew off the there was dust all over the map, so I blew the dust off the maps. Oh, okay. Okay.
>> Yeah. That's that's definitely something we don't want you to be doing. So we we wanna get that taken care of as soon as possible.
Alright.
9 I Wheeling Road property
request discussion.
>> Where are we? I guess that
the what the easements from the state that you can't sell any of that property.
So
we can't I I guess this the sale went through with
the Sheehan's,
and they do have access
to their property from Sheehan's
from
from Wheeling Road.
There's no need to give anybody an access.
>> Okay.
Then we can sit there and take this off of our future Take
this off to those. So basically, can take we can take the
no, everything else. We can take the veterans field improvement off this agenda.
And we can take Wheeling Road property discussion off the agenda next month. Right?
Jay, discussion of possible action on the town administrators contract.
We do need to sit there and get that completed. The there is an issue that we were trying to address.
This will be signed by our next meeting.
Matt, we will have a fit full contract
to put into the packet and make sure that the community has it so we can all sit there and see it, and we'll go from there. Right?
Town
buildings code of conduct. I know we have that in our in our packet.
>> So
I talked to Dennis today, and he had looked at it. He's written something similar to that
with Mansfield, but I also had a talk with
First Select about perhaps posting something
not as
detailed, but something that like say at the I think it was the
University of Connecticut has some things that they have posted which have like just about five or six bullet points just to say just remind people that you're in a public building, you know, be kind, it doesn't cost anything.
>> Yeah.
So I had shared with
Matt,
when this came up probably about a month ago, I had been
at my doctor's office at the UConn Medical Center, and they all have signage
as to behavior
for
people coming into the facility.
And I took a picture and shared it with Matt. It's,
we should put the actual form and have Dennis sit there and update it for next month. But my whole thought was we should be posting things
at the tax collector's desk, at the front door, at the town clerk's desk, that behavior and certain behavior won't be tolerated so that the residents are aware. Alright?
Okay.
Nine l,
event permits. We
have,
an event permit in our packet from,
Norton trick or treat. So, Charlotte Nelson is
is
spearheading this. She's the contact information. It's gonna be a road race to benefit the Norton Children's Fund.
It's scheduled for tentwenty four.
So Charlotte is definitely ahead of our ninety day window.
And
she is going to work with the
various groups, the cert a state trooper and Matt as to potentially
closing
or to utilizing School Road on that day,
for the race. So,
the,
I mean, approving the permit is, is no problem for me.
Having the details,
identified with Matt and with, all the related parties is what's more important.
So,
I have no problem. I'll make a motion to approve
the Norton commission
trick or trot,
event scheduled for 10/24/2026.
Second that.
>> And a second, further discussion on
the permit application and what it's for.
It's a
it's a charity charity race for
the Norton,
the Norton Children's Fund.
Okay.
Anyway, nothing. Alright. So
call vote. Anne, how do you vote?
Scott, how do you vote?
Aye. Jeff McGuire votes yes. So we all voted, so it's three nothing on that.
In our packet also is,
this was spearheaded by Jeff Murray
related to trying to get the permits in on time,
and
it is really something that we should sit there and do. I would ask that we probably
firm this up and get with Dennis Matt and make sure that we know that this this ordinance, and I believe Dennis, you're probably gonna sit there and say you gotta pass the ordinance.
So it'll be a minor ordinance, but it's something that we should do to sit there and get,
a little bit more structure in our permitting process.
And if the groups,
you know, we probably should look at some kind of fee side. There are some information and fees here. I think we gotta tighten that up. But,
if people come to us last minute and they want a permit, you know,
we really, and we start to jump through hoops as a town, we should be charging them. So,
Charlotte and the Norton Commission did a great job getting us well
in advance so we understand what's up, we can communicate to the residents as to what's going to happen. And I
think it's a, I think this is something that we desperately
need because we do get all of these groups that come in last second and try to just throw these events. And we're, we've always tried to accommodate everybody because
there's no reason not to, but it does become problematic.
Anybody have any other issues related to that?
Okay.
Item 10A has been deleted from the,
agenda. Item 10B,
a discussion and action on signatory resolution.
>> Yes. So for OPM,
we have
for the last fiscal year for the community,
the old burial grounds, they had a grant.
But they need somebody that's a signatory to sign off on it. And
it's probably something that is
being needed for other state
grants. So I'm asking if the
resolution can be passed that
appoints me as a signatory for the town for OPM and other state
agencies
dealing with grants.
>> I have no problem. I'll make a motion to appoint Matt
town administrator, Matt Streeter, as a signatory
will pass a signatory author a resolution authorizing me to sign,
on behalf of the town.
Back at that, Jeff.
>> K.
Further discussion, Matt, you will have this drafted
and then presented to all of the members of the board of selectmen so they're all aware of what I'm gonna sign before I sign it. Absolutely.
I think it's Alright. It's in our packet.
It
>> is. Isn't it? I didn't I didn't see. That's the draft one.
>> There there is something in there about that. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I thought it got in there.
I'm trying to find it.
No. After it's under new business.
>> Yeah. So completed. It's like a draft. Mhmm. Completed. Make sure that it it does everything that we need to do, and we'll get it signed in draft.
Right? But still send out the final one to all of the
the members so that we can do it. And if we all need to sign it, we can all get into the town hall at some point in time and get it signed. But I would say,
well,
>> let's all sign it so everybody's Yeah. What I would do is I put all this all five selectmen's name on so that,
you know, obviously,
you'll resolve to resolve tonight. And then they'll you know, once they've been sworn in, they can come into my office and sign it. We'll put all the names on it.
>> Okay.
Alright. So
I'm gonna call that for a vote. Anne, how do you vote?
Scott, how do you vote?
>> Okay. Jeff, every, the other two selectmen did vote yes.
So the vote was three nothing. So there's a little bit of lag in what's going on to
go from there.
Discussion and action on the fire department compressors,
>> request item 10. Yeah. That should be taken off.
I think that we initially,
there was a thought that the select board need to approve it after discussion with both first, selectmen
that this was already a budgetary item that was approved prior. So they can I I told, Wally that they can just go ahead and order the compressor? It didn't need further select board approval.
>> K.
Alright. Anybody have any issues with that? I mean, I know we've talked about this compressor system multiple times. K.
Item 10 d, we've already done that.
Item 10 E, discussion and possible action on the school town van usage contract.
Matt, where are we?
>> We are, Tess and I are
working with the administration
and the principal over there. I think we should have something
firmed up shortly.
>> I don't know if Tess has anything more to add or not. Is that something that we're going to have to sit there and have a special meeting to approve or what is the status of what's going to happen?
>> It could be either way. Think that, you know, if we want to, if you guys would like to see it, then I can definitely send it around. If there's a
general consensus that we move forward that the town administrator can sign it on their your behalf. I'd be happy to do that too.
>> Okay. We'll send it around, and we'll sit there and approve it on a
an email basis if no one else has any problems. Are there some some concerns that Tess had?
Tess?
>> I think we're okay on the mileage, just not sure about the gas
reimbursement
or not. So I think we're hopeful that we are coming to a conclusion that we're all getting
along well, and we look forward to what the new school year looks like. So
I think we'll be able to
iron out all those little details.
Gas reimbursement?
I mean, isn't it a mileage contract?
>> It is a mileage contract, but I think there was a confusion there if they were paying mileage and gas.
But
I think we're just trying to figure out what what that full contract looks like.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
All right. Please get with Dennis on that so that Dennis is aware of that on. Yeah. I would be happy to approve that as the form.
Okay.
Yeah.
>> Alright.
Nine, 10 F, discussion and possible action on the Bozzola Road Culvert.
>> Matt, is there something that we need to do related to that? No. It's just that other than that we're gonna start moving forward with trying to get the easements, it's preliminary.
Everything's gonna come back to you before we get get to that step.
So at this point, there's nothing to approve. Just that we're gonna, you know, they aren't I think the main decision is that we are gonna move forward to try to get the easements this year. The discussion prior to was whether we're gonna get it in time or whether we're gonna need another extension into next year. So I think we're moving forward this year. Okay.
>> So who
have we decided are going to do or write in the easements?
>> I
think that we have between
Dennis and the engineers, the engineers said they would do as little or as much as we want. I think they gave us a draft. I'm gonna work with Dennis to see if that's something that we can just come up with something. But if we have to meet with them on-site, the engineer is welcome to come in or is offered
that he could come and, you know, help show them exactly where on the properties that they're talking about. I think there's three
temporary easements
and
three
small permanent easements. But one of the temporary easements is considerable easement because they're gonna have to move the road slightly to accommodate
the construction. And, of course, that road's gonna be closed for three to four, five months during the construction.
>> Alright. All of the residents had been made aware all of the impacted residents and the impacted property owners have been made aware of the project, what we need to do, and Matt, what I want to get done is is have a group meeting,
with Dennis, the engineer, and all of the residents that are impacted. If we can get a scheduled meeting to get them all in one spot to talk about the value of the project and what it's gonna do,
I think it would help and go a long way to get the easements signed timely.
So it's something that we probably need to do now because this is a as as Scott, you mentioned, it's a a 2027
project,
not a 2026, it's a 2027 project. It is a project.
But it is gonna cause,
it's gonna cause considerable
heartache having Lake Road
closed in that direction.
>> And the engineers go out and mark out where these easements are gonna be so the landowners know where they are. So, and then to get everybody together is because it seems like it's not
moving along very well.
>> We only talk we we only just I only just met with them today for the first time. So it was one of those so I don't think it's really been
moved forward because we haven't started to. But now that we are, I would recommend that we probably do not have a group meeting with all of them. The engineer recommended that we probably meet with them individually.
I think what his concern would be is that if you start talking to one that, you know, when you start doing some negotiations
for compensation
or
others
in lieu of,
like, removing bushes or doing some other yard yard escaping
that, the other people will say, well, I'd like that too. I'd like that too. So I think that,
>> their best yeah. And I'd be willing to talk to them. And, no, that's actually a really good idea. And, Christine, this is something that you can get engaged in because it's something that we're gonna have to sit there and make their yards back to
the original condition, especially one of the residents like Matt said. So that'd be very good to have Christine engaged in that because a lot of it'll be landscaping work.
Okay.
That's great. Thank you. I I agree with that, Matt, individually.
Especially with one resident,
you know, we probably need to get that one resident done first
because that's gonna be the key to get the project completed.
Right?
So
okay.
Anything else?
>> Just on that the the contract with the engineer has had a has laughed or continuing on. I we don't have anything in writing yet, but we will be probably moving forward to keep
Jacobson Associates
engaged. They're willing to stay on, and it's just that they originally signed a three year contract, and it sort of just quietly expired. It was on June 29 that I actually looked at it and realized that it was that that's when I made the contact with the engineer,
Howard Frommer, and
he he was unaware that it was expiring. So that's when we set up the meeting for for today. And so we'll we'll we'll have something by the next meeting, hopefully, that we can put eye put eyes on.
>> And so the intention is to extend the contract without any increase in the the contracted fee?
>> Yeah. We have like I said, we haven't even started any, negotiations. I would rather, you know, talk to the select board and see where we're gonna go as far as any fees or anything if they're gonna offer anything. So
>> Okay.
Alright.
Anything else related to this item, the other members?
No? Okay.
We're gonna move on to item 11, approval of minute meetings for May 11, June 8, and June 19, special meeting.
Anybody have any corrections to the minute meetings
or the the minutes?
No.
K.
>> Then I make a motion that we approve the May eleventh twenty twenty six regular minute meetings, the June eighth twenty twenty six regular minute meetings, and the 06/19/2026
special meeting minutes.
Second that, Jeff.
>> Scott Persona seconded.
Any further discussion on any of the the minutes?
Alright. Anne, how do you vote?
And votes yes. Scott?
Yes.
>> Jeff McGuire votes yes. Three nothing.
Item 12, the tax collector's report that starts in our packet on page 54.
June was, last month in the quarter, so very slow. July is much faster. She you know, the tax collector's getting
daily visits from all the residents.
So we'll sit there and see a much larger pickup in total deposit in deposits.
Page 57 is the delinquent taxpayers. I like that the list is shrinking. It's always good when people pay their taxes.
And anybody else have any other issues?
Okay,
we're going to move on to item 13, departmental reports.
We have a report from the assessor.
So the assessors reports goes to like 63,
60, you know, it goes further than that.
No, 63.
And
you have burn permits that we can sit there and see. That's the first time I've seen that one. And we have building department
reports. And does anybody have any?
Matt, I would sit there and ask you to,
you once you get to like page 73,
please do not include the items from
down on the building department. She just provided you with information and it got dumped into the
packet. That's not information that we wanna sit there and have in a packet. Okay.
Section page 92
are the,
are our blight
information,
good information. Scott, you have any issues on that?
>> I didn't see anything new, yeah, lately.
But I am going down to the building department to go over a few things with her.
I I saw some things that weren't.
They're probably fine, but I just I wanna understand a few things that are written in there. Yeah. I don't understand some things either in the
permits.
Okay.
>> The dates
are after the property had been sold to somebody else. So I
There's two properties like that. Yeah. I see at least two that I know of.
>> Okay.
So
Scott, when you get down there, give us a report as to what information you find out when you come back. You know, that'll help the other members.
Page 96,
we have some information related to,
summer road work from,
Department of Public Works.
I think that Matt and
the other members of the board, we need to sit there and be
working
to get with Eric and sit there and see what they're doing. I think it'd be very beneficial for each one of us to sit there and get some understanding as to what they're working on
and getting out and seeing them work.
I think it's important for us to sit there and have a good feel for what they're doing because they're the ones who are doing the road work and making sure that we sit there and have
the best possible roads we can have to drive on.
>> And to maybe ask Eric if he I don't know what you guys think, but
if he could put up, a whiteboard with everybody's names and where they're working daily. So if we we go down there and then we can go see see what they're doing. I don't I don't know if that's too, intrusive
or
>> No. I don't think it is. But, Matt, if you could sit there and work with Eric as to how we can sit there and accomplish something like that, I think it's really important for us to know where our crews
are because
it'll be helpful for all of us to understand where they are and what they're doing. So,
Matt, if you could work something out, that would be great.
On page 97,
we have some information related to from the tree warden. And,
you know, Zach is sitting there telling us that certain trees were down. I mean, we did have
recently,
you know, a couple of events that some trees did come down, which is rare. I mean, we haven't had very many trees come down. We've had a couple on Lake Road that have
impacted power. So but I think the tree I think the money we've invested in
are
reducing our dead trees has really helped
>> keep our power on in town. So And Eric tells me about that that Coventry where he came from, the trees were coming down everywhere,
and he does not see that in Andover. We we did a really good job with the trees.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
Matt, this this Department of Transportation memo, let's sit there and see what we're supposed to be getting related to,
the
signage,
and
where we can potentially put it.
>> So
I think that they're just replacing all the signs.
>> They are replacing all the signs.
Alright. So this is not a speed sign. This is just that work of replacing the signs. I got it. Yeah. Right.
Speed limit signs or street signs? Street signs.
>> I mean It is? Yeah. It's on state roads. So
actually, it's more than state roads.
Yeah. It's all I read I read the issue, Anne. I read I read what the state was doing. They were,
they were taking down signage and then putting up more signage. So there is actually more signage going up in town as far as road issues.
Probably need to get that letter back in the packet, Matt, for maybe next meeting. There was a letter that explained what the state was doing related to this. I just have forgotten it.
Good.
Alright.
And over public library starts on page a 100,
and then we have the ROV
monthly activity,
on page one zero one.
Anybody have any questions related to any departmental reports?
What I'd also like to do is
I'd like to start getting
various other
chairpersons or different departments on our meetings in the beginning of our meetings, to give us just brief updates as to what they're working on, and what's happening with their department. So I think it would be really helpful to
sit there and get some other,
have
Matt sit there and direct and get some of the other department heads on our meeting to just talk about what they're doing and to sit there and give the community some understanding of how they're utilizing their budget and for what benefit for the town. So I think it would be positive to do that.
Right, we'll move on to item 14 correspondence,
Matt. We don't have any, is that accurate?
Correct.
And we're gonna move on to item 15, which is public speak. So
we're gonna start with, phone number ending in 5475.
>> Hi, this is Leanne.
Nothing further. Thanks anyway again. Okay. Scott Salliette.
>> Just quickly, thank you very much for the amazingly efficient process, quick process this time for replacing the,
Selectman.
Thanks to Ron and Jacqueline and Ben for putting themselves forward.
And, congratulations to Christine and Dave,
but also condolences as well.
I hope Jeff, Scott, and Anne are able to tell you that it's rewarding,
but I also know it's pretty thankless a lot of the time. So good luck.
Alright. Valerie Burto?
>> I echo that. Glad to see all of the
townspeople that were interested in joining a board.
And congratulations,
Dave. And
I don't see if she's oh, yeah. And Christine, she's still on there. Yes, congratulations.
Tess Grauss.
>> I agree with the congratulations
with Christine and Dave, and I invite you all to come to the Community and Senior Center to meet
miss Cox and hope to see you soon.
Okay.
Caitlin Greenhouse.
>> I'm really pleased to see you guys be able to appoint two selectmen so that have a full board again. That's awesome. I also just wanted to remind everyone, we'll continue to to give updates on the bathroom project.
We do have weekly meetings for that, which Matt has been able to attend as well. So we'll make sure to try to keep everyone abreast of that as it progresses throughout the summer. Thank you.
>> Nick?
No comment at this time. Thank you.
Heather Von Kara?
>> No comment. Just welcome Christine and Dave. Looking forward to working with you.
Louise Loquatch.
>> You
took the words out of my mouth, Heather. Yes. Welcome
Christine and Dave, and thank you
to
everyone who applied.
Throw their hat in the ring.
Appreciate you all, and thank you for a good meeting tonight.
>> Wally?
Nothing at this time, but thank you for the compressor.
Alright.
Marci Miner?
>> Hi. Yeah. Same thing. Thank you for a great meeting. It's, really good to see, and I look forward to the future.
Alright. Diane Greiner?
No. Unmute.
Technical.
>> Ah, okay. I'm technically challenged. I'm so glad Dave Gustanian's on board.
Yes. Again, I'll echo what everybody else said. Welcome to Christine and Dave, and thanks to all the others who did show interest in serving on the board of Selectmen.
It's a tough job, and I wish him well.
I also
I like the idea that
Jeff McGuire has put forward about having
chairman of the different boards come and tell us what they're doing. I think that's a good idea, and I applaud you for that, and I look forward to seeing that. So thank you all. Good meeting. No
drama,
which is always a good thing. Thank you. Or cast. Joanne Hebert.
>> I was just going to echo the same thing that
five impressive candidates came forward today,
and anybody that was open minded and never had heard from them before,
you know, they all gave great
ideas or reasons for wanting to serve the public. So I was definitely impressed.
And I wish everybody good luck and looking
forward to seeing them in action.
>> Right.
Leanne Hutchinson, I believe you already got an opportunity. Is that accurate?
Yes, it is. Thanks. Okay. Okay. No problem. All right. I'm gonna go, Christine Randazzo because you're still a member of the public.
>> This was a great meeting. I appreciate and honor the opportunity to serve on the board. I'm looking forward to working with everybody.
Dave Gustavian.
>> Yes.
I echo
Christine's remarks.
I'm looking forward to helping and I appreciate the
>> support of the townspeople and the board. Thank you. All right. And Dennis O'Brien, you can close this out because you remember the public and I haven't given you an opportunity to speak, but
>> you're on a shortly. I know why the
chief because, you know, I would go on and on. This meeting is about to end before 09:00.
And I'm impressed by that. It was a great meeting.
A lot accomplished.
I'm looking forward to working with
the new members, and you you just did a great thing hiring
Kate McCarthy Cox, who I've known since she was a little kid. She will be great. Great addition to the town of Andover.
Wonderful. Things are going very well. Everybody's working together. Love it. Thank you.
>> Okay.
Alright. Did I miss anyone?
All right.
If that's it, I'm going to make a motion to adjourn.
Second. Second that Jeff.
>> Anne seconded. She won that one. All right.
Further discussion? No. All those in favor? Anne?
Okay.
>> Scott?
Aye.
Jeff Maguire. Yes. Thank you very much, everybody. Appreciate your time. Yeah. Thank you. Alright.
Bye, guys.